Yuan LYU

UX/Interaction Designer

EXPERIENCE

- UX/UI Design Intern, Volkswagen AG
 Smart Mobility&Transport, Berlin, Germany
 Oct.2018 ~ Present
 - Iterate the UX design based on user research feedback
 - Master the persona profile, customer journey
 - Create the UI library for the style guide, redesign the landing page
 - Innovation Intern, F. Hoffmann La-Roche AG Finance, Diagnostics IT, Basel, Switzerland Nov.2017 ~ Apr. 2018
 - Contributed to key projects(SAP, personalized healthcare) as UX Designer, designed concepts, created wireframes, etc.
 - Designed and implemented the UCD curriculum, drove cross-team knowledge building agenda on usability
 - Created and facilitated Design Sprint workshop
- Master Thesis Student, Technische Universität Berlin
 Quality and Usability Lab, Berlin, Germany Jul.2017 ~ May.2018

 Concept Design for Pedestrian-Vehicle Communication in the Age
 of Autonomous Driving
 - Product Design Working Student, Care Campanion GmbH.

 Product Team, Berlin, Germany

 Jul.2017 ~ Oct.2017
 - Concepting and designing for main website and new landing page
 - Analyzing user journey, preparing&executing user research activities
 - Co-operating with senior designer, product managers and developer
 - Product Support Working Student, Jovoto GmbH.

Product Team, Berlin, Germany

Mar.2017 ~ *May.2017*

- Created user flows and wireframes for products concept papers
- Technically translated internal as well as external bug reports
- Validated and enriched bug reports with all needed information
- **UX Intern**, FOTILE Kitchen Ware Co. Ltd.

Innovation Institute, Ningbo, China

Oct.2014 ~ Jan.2015

- Co-designed interface for new oven, steam box and microwave oven
- Implement the high-fidelity Prototype individually
- Made reasonable user test script, participated in usability research

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Human Computer Interaction and Design

Double Degree Degree EIT Digital Merit Scholarship 2016/2017

Technische Universität Berlin, Germany

Oct.2016 ~ Present

Université Paris-Sud, France

Sep.2015 ~ Jun.2016

Bachelor of Engineering in Network Engineering

Dalian Maritime University, China

Sep.2011 ~ Jun.2015

- **+49(0)157-3326-2956**
- yuan.lyu@hotmail.com
- http://yuan-lyu.com
- Berlin, Germany 10963

PROFILE

As a hybrid designer with programming experiences, I am adept at understanding of user story, and always have the passion to use my creativity to solve unusual problems and design for uncommon products.

Sincerely look forward to a position in the area of Interaction and UX Design.

SKILLS

DESIGN

In-Depth Interview
Questionnaire
Persona | Scenario
Conceptual Storyboard
Wireframing
Prototyping
Usability Test
Sketch / Photoshop
Axure / InVision / Principle
Balsamiq / OmniGraffle

PROGRAMMING

JAVA / C#
HTML / CSS
ASP.NET
SQL Server / MySQL
JavaScript
Unity (Virtual Reality)
Arduino / Processing
Node.js

LANGUAGE

Chinese: Native English: Fluent German: Beginner